Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/arjunsalyan (LinkedIn) arjunsalyan.com (Blog) www.github.com/arjunsalyan (Other)

Top Skills

Python Web Development Node.js

Honors-Awards Science Day Honour Gold Medal Regional Finalist

Arjun Salyan

GSoC 19, 20 | IIT (BHU) | DevOps | Cloud | Full Stack Varanasi

Summary

I am an engineering student actively involved in software development since secondary school. Recently, I have also entered the fields of cloud computing and devops.

I wrote my first website in 7th standard and started an informal business in 6th standard. I have not stopped since then. Numerous freelance projects, open source activities, internships and personal projects have helped me excel in web and app development. To know more about my technical skillset and works please visit arjunsalyan.com.

I love development, I love making things which a user can benefit from. I am self-taught when it comes to any concept related to a computer.

This love is a consequence of a feeling I carry with me- and that is-building products which can ease down a process or experience. This feeling is what drove me into the geeky stuff. There is a different kind of excitement in researching over the user needs, finding a solution and then implementing it. I wish I could emphasise it more. The last part, 'implementation' drove me into learning to build my own tools- digital tools. If I try to find an analogy, then I can be compared to a cook who loves serving delicious but healthy food. And to achieve his idea of health- he starts to grow his own vegetables and spices. I am sorry if this sounds absurd, but in this paragraph I am simply writing as if we are having a conversation, as if I am telling you the basis of every single line of code I have written in my life, as if I am speaking my heart to you.

Experience

Google Summer of Code Student Developer May 2020 - Present (4 months) Semut Labs Cloud Native Engineer - Intern April 2020 - June 2020 (3 months)

Kashiyatra, IIT (BHU) Varanasi Head Of Public Relations July 2019 - February 2020 (8 months)

Google Summer of Code Student Developer at MacPorts May 2019 - August 2019 (4 months)

Digi Infy Full Stack Developer July 2018 - March 2019 (9 months)

Worked successfully with two clients:

- 1. BGIS, Mathura: Developed their admissions management portal, donations portal, internal support-tickets system and website.
- 2. Natural Ice Creams: Developed store locator and website.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology (Banaras Hindu University), Varanasi B.Tech · (2017 - 2021)